AKANSHA GUPTA

• 061-412-624333 • akanshagupta939@gmail.com LinkedIn Profile

Professional Summary

A passionate Software developer offering a wealth of 3 years of expertise. I have touched bases with the diverse programming languages, including Java, Python, SQL, No SQL and JavaScript. Hailing from an engineering background, I hope to make the transition to coding by linking and integrating values and believe to ace it if given the right attitude with a passion, which aligns with my values and belief of changing the world.

Education

Masters: Information and Technology, 2019 – Nov-2020

Monash University - Australia

Bachelor's: Computer Science and Engineering, 2015

Uttar Pradesh Technical University- India

Work History

See-mode - Australia

Junior Software Engineer (Full-time)12/2020-Present, Software Engineer (Part-time), 7/2020 to 11/2020

Developed a product, which enables clinicians to predict stroke, by using deep learning, it analyses each individual image in a vascular ultrasound scan, while giving you full control to easily amend the results.

- Used Typescript and Angular Js to build new functionality of application build on Ngrx Platform using Dixie Server and AWS
- Handle medium and high priority stories and run test case scenarios to avoid any future failure.
- Maintaining high integrity by ensuring the delivery of software of the highest standards in a timely manner by following Agile Methodologies.

IT Developer/E2E Designer, 11/2019 to 6/2019

Point Cook Tutoring-Australia (Part-time, working on cash)

An Australia based start-up that provides tutoring services for students who struggles with their studies.

- Prepared design documents & prototype through client interaction and understanding their requirements.
- Developed website using PHP, HTML/CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Collaborated with graphic designer to implement new graphics and design within the web page
- Creating Database from scratch using PhpMyAdmin.

Software Developer/E2E Designer, 03/2018 to 01/2019

FlyAway Corporation-India (Full-time)

An Indian based start-up that has expanded internationally (Italy and Melbourne). Works on digital marketing and web-based development.

- Prepared design documents through client interaction and time management skills.
- Fixed bugs along with providing constant support to the testers and maintain the deployments.
- Strong team player and handle complicated issues related to the deployment of Python based applications along with .Net & MVC projects.
- Kept project hosted on GitHub for Continuous Integration/ Deployments.

Assistant System Engineer, 12/2015 to 03/2018

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, India (Full-time)

Tata Consultancy Services Limited (TCS) is an Indian multinational IT service and consulting company

- Ensured all acceptance criteria of STORM story are met and eliminated defects & bugs during system integration and E2E testing in Prebuilt British Telecom application.
- Deployed 5- 6 stories, each of 30 + story points, which were based on Java and Relational Database as well as Spring Hibernate using tools like Eclipse & MySQL.
- Worked on Spring Framework and ORM Technologies.
- Revised an application that would help the project and test team to collaborate and reduce the testing requirements and delivering a quality and extensible product.

Skills

- Core Java
- UNIX/PowerShell (Basic)
- HTML/CSS/Wordpress
- SQL and Heidi SQL
- Python
- .Net & MVC (C#)
- PHP (basics)
- R Studio and Tableau

- Angular JS
- Typescript
- NoSQL (Mongo, Cassandra & Neo4j)
- Experience with Agile Delivery & methodologies
- Kubernetes and AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda)
- Familiar with Docker and Kubernetes
- Version Control (Git, Bit Bucket,SVN)

Certifications

- Microsoft Certified Professional in Operating System
- Microsoft Certified Professional in Networking
- Certificate of Machine Learning A-Z: Hands-on Python and R in Data Science
- Certified Java Programmer by Oracle Workforce Development Program

- Certified in C by APTECH Computer Education
- Apache Spark for Java Developers

PROJECT INVOLVEMENT:

07/2020 - 11-2020

BushfireAssist, (Website Link, Password: Ta18@2020)

An application build to help residents in bushfire prone regions that are the most adversely affected during times of this natural hazard like bushfire which ensure that every single resident can persist in such challenging times

- Application is hosted on AWS by using AWS services likes EC2 instance and Route53
- Application is built on Wordpress by coding at the backend of the application using PHP, HTML & CSS
- Data is been incorporated after wrangling it on R and Python
- Security feature is enabled in the app by using AWS SSL security services

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT:

04/2020 - Present

Customer Care Representative, Woolworth

Woolworths is an Australian chain of supermarkets and grocery stores owned by Woolworths Group.

- Handle 90+ customer daily, with duties including stocking the items and introducing them with new items in the store.
- Trained two new employees in how to use Woolworth system, scanning items and bagging them efficiently.
- Received an average 85% customer satisfaction rating to date, 15% higher than company average

03/2019 - Present

CASHIER and SERVERY, Obrien Group

O'Brien Group is Australia and New Zealand's largest privately-owned hospitality, entertainment and leisure company.

- Used card and EFTPOS facilities to process transactions and cross-checked all the transactions after my shift, ensuring there were 0 discrepancies in reconciliations.
- Provided exceptional customer service by active listening and ensuring customer have a good experience and get their orders on time.
- Liaised with supplies to place an order and ensure stock levels were delivered on time.

2019 - 2020

VOLUNTEER,

TEDx Monash University

- Attend clubs' meetings, setting up events, respond to event enquiries.
- Promote the events that are organised by TEDx

Reference: